pwc.com 2019-12-25

# Privacy Statement: PwC

#### **Business contacts**

##### **Information collection​ ​**

We collect and use business contact details for individuals associated with existing and potential PwC clients to manage and maintain our relationship with those individuals. Like most businesses, we use a customer relationship management system (the “PwC CRM”) to store personal information about our business contacts. 

The collection of personal information about contacts and the addition of that personal information to the PwC CRM is initiated by PwC staff and may include name, employer name, title, phone, email and other business contact details. In addition, the PwC CRM may collect data from PwC email and calendar systems concerning interactions between PwC staff and business contacts. 

When we send you emails, we may use technologies to determine whether the email has been opened and whether the links contained within the message have been clicked on. We may combine information collected through these means with other information we maintain about you to measure interest in our specific offerings and email campaigns, improve our offerings to specific target audiences, and tailor our interactions with you.

##### **Information use**

We use this information for the following business purposes:

  * **Administering, managing and developing our business and services.** We may process personal information to run our business, including:
    * managing our relationship with clients; ****
    * providing services and customer support to our clients;
    * developing our business and services, such as identifying client needs and improvements in service delivery and learning more about a client relationship opportunity we or other PwC member firms have an interest in; ****
    * analyzing and evaluating the strength of interactions between PwC and a contact  (e.g., the PwC CRM uses an algorithm to help with this analysis, and the ranking is primarily based on interaction frequency, duration, recency and response time); ****
    * performing analytics, including producing metrics for PwC leadership, such as on trends, relationship maps, sales intelligence, and progress against account business goals; ****
    *  maintaining and using IT systems; ****
    * hosting or facilitating the hosting of events; and ****
    * administering and managing our website, systems, and applications.
  * **Providing information about us and our range of services**

Unless we are asked not to, we use client business contact details to provide information that we think will be of interest about PwC and our services. For example, we may send you industry updates and insights, information about other services that may be relevant to you, and invites to events.

Please review the **Your choices ** _ _**** section below for information about how you may unsubscribe from our mailing lists and exercise other rights.

##### **Information retention**

Personal information will be retained in the PwC CRM for as long as we have, or need to keep a record of, a relationship with a business contact. Personal information may be held for longer periods where extended retention periods are required by law, regulation, or professional standards and to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights. 

##### **Information sharing**

We may share personal information with third parties as described in the **Information disclosure** section below.

In addition, our business contacts are visible to and may be used by other PwC member firms to learn more about a contact, client or opportunity they have an interest in.

##### **Your California privacy rights**

If you are a California resident, please click here for additional information about our processing of personal information and your California privacy rights.

#### **Corporate clients (and individuals associated with our corporate clients)**

Our policy is to collect only the personal information necessary for agreed purposes, and we ask our clients only to share personal information with us when it is needed for those purposes.  When we need to process personal information to provide our services, we ask our clients to provide the necessary information to the data subjects concerned regarding how PwC will process that personal information, as our clients are typically in the appropriate position to communicate this information to the data subjects (e.g., our clients’ employees or our clients’ customers).

##### **Information collection**

Given the diversity of services we provide to clients ([click here for information on our services](https://www.pwc.com/us/en/services.html)), we process many categories of personal information, which may include:

  * Personal details (e.g., name, age/date of birth, gender, marital status, country of residence);
  * Contact details (e.g., email address, phone number, postal address);
  * Financial details (e.g., salary, payroll details and other financial-related details such as income, investments and other financial interests, benefits, tax status);
  * Job details (e.g., role, grade, experience, performance information and other information about management and employees); and
  * For certain client engagements, we may process sensitive or special categories of personal information (such as in performing know your client checks, which may involve us processing government identification documents that may contain biometric data).

Generally, we collect personal information from our clients or from third parties acting on the instructions of the client. 

##### **Information use**

We use the above personal information for the following business purposes:

  * **Providing professional services and products  
**We provide a diverse range of professional services ([click here for information on our services](https://www.pwc.com/us/en/services.html)) and products. Some of our services require us to process personal information to provide advice and deliverables. 
  * **Security, quality and risk management activities**
    * Personal information may be processed as part of the security monitoring that we undertake to detect, investigate and resolve security threats — for example, automated scans to identify harmful emails (e.g., phishing attempts).
    *  We monitor the services provided to clients for quality purposes and risk management purposes, which may involve processing personal information stored on the relevant client file.
    * We collect and hold personal information as part of our client engagement and acceptance procedures, including carrying out searches using publicly available sources — such as internet searches and sanctions lists — to help identify politically exposed persons and heightened risk individuals and organizations and checking that there are no issues that would prevent us from working with a particular client — such as sanctions, criminal convictions, conduct or other reputational issues, including with respect to company directors.
  * **Complying with any requirement of law, regulation or a professional body of which we are a member**

As with any provider of professional services, we are subject to legal, regulatory and professional obligations. Subject to these obligations, and as described in the **Information retention** section below, we need to keep certain records to demonstrate that our services are provided in compliance with those obligations, and those records may contain personal information.

We are continually looking for ways to help our clients and improve our business and services.  Where agreed with our clients, we may use information that we receive in the course of providing professional services for other lawful purposes, including analysis to better understand a particular issue, industry or sector, provide insights to our clients, improve our business, service delivery and offerings and develop new PwC technologies and offerings.  To the extent that the information we receive in the course of providing professional services contains personal information, we will de-identify the information prior to using it for these purposes.

##### **Information retention**

We retain the personal information processed by us for as long as is considered necessary for the purpose for which it was collected. Personal information may be held for longer periods where extended retention periods are required by law, regulation, or professional standards and to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights.

##### **Information sharing**

We may share personal information with third parties as described in the **Information disclosure** section below.

In addition, we may share personal information with:

  * **Third party organizations that assist us in providing services  
**On certain client engagements, pursuant to our agreements with such clients, we may engage or otherwise work with other providers to help us provide professional services to our clients.
  * **Our clients  
**Where we need to process personal information to provide professional services to our clients, we may share personal information in our deliverables, such as the reports we create.

##### **Your California privacy rights**

If you are a California resident, please ****click here for additional information about our processing of personal information and your California privacy rights.

#### **Individual clients of PwC services**

We may provide a separate privacy statement in connection with certain services provided to individuals, and where we do so, such privacy statement will apply to our processing of personal information in the performance of those services.

Generally, our policy is to collect only the personal information necessary for agreed purposes, and we ask our clients only to share personal information when it is needed for those purposes.  When we need to process personal information relating to individuals other than our clients to provide our services, we ask our clients to provide the necessary information to other data subjects concerned, such as family members, regarding its use.

##### **Information collection**

Given the diversity of the services we provide to individual clients ([click here for information on our services](https://www.pwc.com/us/en/services.html)), we process many categories of personal information, including as appropriate for the services we are providing:

  * contact details (e.g., email address, phone number, postal address);
  * business activities (e.g., job details, role, experience);
  * family information (e.g., dependents and other household information); and
  * financial details (e.g., salary, payroll details and other financial-related details such as income, investments and other financial interests, benefits, tax status).

For certain services, and when permitted by law, we may also collect sensitive or special categories of personal information. Examples of special categories include race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, physical or mental health, genetic data, biometric data, sexual life or sexual orientation, and criminal records.

Generally, we collect personal information directly from our clients or from a third party acting on the instructions of the client. 

##### **Information use**

We use personal information for the following business purposes:

  * **Providing professional services.  **We provide a diverse range of professional services ([click here for information on our services](https://www.pwc.com/us/en/services.html)). Some of our services require us to process personal information to provide advice and deliverables. For example, we may use personal information to provide individual tax advice, immigration services or pension advice.
  * **Administering, managing and developing our businesses and services.  **We may process personal information to run our business, including:
    * managing our relationship with clients;
    * developing our businesses and services (such as identifying client needs and improvements in service delivery);
    * maintaining and using IT systems;
    * hosting or facilitating the hosting of events; and
    * administering and managing our website and systems and applications.
  * **Security, quality and risk management activities**
    * Personal information may be processed as part of the security monitoring that we undertake. For example, automated scans to identify harmful emails.
    * We monitor the services provided to clients for quality purposes, which may involve processing personal information stored in the relevant client file. We have policies and procedures in place to monitor the quality of our services and manage risks in relation to client engagements.
    * We collect and hold personal information as part of our client engagement and acceptance procedures, including carrying out searches using publicly available sources — such as internet searches and sanctions lists — to help identify politically exposed persons and heightened risk individuals and organizations and checking that there are no issues that would prevent us from working with a particular client — such as sanctions, criminal convictions, conduct or other reputational issues, including with respect to company directors.
  * **Providing our clients and prospective clients with information about us and our range of services.  **With consent or otherwise in accordance with applicable law, we use client contact details to provide information that we think will be of interest about us and our services — for example, industry updates and insights, other services that may be relevant and invites to events.
  * **Complying with any requirement of law, regulation or a professional body of which we are a member.  **As with any provider of professional services, we are subject to legal, regulatory and professional obligations.  Subject to these obligations, as described in the **Information retention** section below, we need to keep certain records to demonstrate that our services are provided in compliance with those obligations and those records may contain personal information.

We are continually looking for ways to help our clients and improve our business and services.  Where agreed with our clients, we may use the information that we receive in the course of providing professional services for other lawful purposes, including analysis to better understand a particular issue, industry or sector, provide insights back to our clients, to improve our business, service delivery and offerings and to develop new PwC technologies and offerings.  To the extent that the information that we receive in the course of providing professional services contains personal information, we will de-identify the information prior to using it for these purposes.

##### **Information retention**

We retain the personal information processed by us for as long as is considered necessary for the purpose for which it was collected. Personal information may be held for longer periods where extended retention periods are required by law, regulation, or professional standards and to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights.

##### **Information sharing**

We may share personal information with third parties as described in the **Information disclosure** section below.

In addition, we may share personal information with:

  * **Third party organizations that assist us in providing services  
**On certain client engagements, pursuant to our agreements with such clients, we may engage or otherwise work with other providers to help us provide professional services to our clients.
  * **Our clients  
**Where we need to process personal information to provide professional services to our clients, we may share personal information in our deliverables (such as the reports we create).

##### **Your California privacy rights**

If you are a California resident, please click here **** for additional information about our processing of personal information and your California privacy rights.

#### **Users of our websites and applications**

This section describes our privacy practices with respect to [https://www.pwc.com](https://www.pwc.com/) and other PwC websites, applications and online services that link to this privacy statement (together referred to as the “Site”).

We may provide a separate privacy statement in connection with certain websites and applications that we offer, and where we do so, such privacy statement will apply to our collection and use of personal information collected through such websites and applications.

##### **Information collection**

When you access or otherwise use our Site, we will collect information about you and how you interact with our Site. We collect information about you through: (1) information you provide; (2) automatic tracking technologies; and (3) third parties.

##### **Information you provide**

When you access our Site, you may choose to provide information about yourself such as your name, address, email address, telephone number, fax number, job title, and company name. By way of example, you may choose to provide your information in the following circumstances:

  * Subscription or ordering newsletters and/or publications;
  * Participation in "join our mailing list" initiatives;
  * Participation in bulletin boards, discussion, or message forums;
  * Entering quick surveys, quizzes or benchmarking surveys;
  * Registration for events and conferences;
  * Registration for premium online services;
  * Contacting us for further information;
  * Visiting our Site while logged into a social media platform.

For information about our collection and use of information received as part of an application for employment submitted through our Site or if you join our Talent Network or Talent Community through our Site, please see the **Sourcing and recruitment of candidates** section of this statement.

##### **Automatically collected information**

We may use online identification technologies, such as cookies, web beacons, or pixels on some pages of our Site (“Tracking Technologies”). The information we collect using these technologies includes: IP address, browser type and language, access time, and referring website. Cookies are small text files placed on your hard drive that assist us in providing a more customized website experience. For example, a cookie can be used to store registration information in an area of the website so that a user does not need to re-enter it on subsequent visits to that area. PwC may use Tracking Technologies from marketing partners on our Site, third party sites, and social media platforms. These Tracking Technologies help to measure the efficacy of our marketing and awareness campaigns and to understand how visitors navigate to our Site from a PwC ad. We use these technologies to compile aggregated statistics about visitors who interact with PwC online content, to gauge the effectiveness of our ads and to better provide more pertinent information to our visitors.

##### **Third-party analytics**

PwC also uses website analytics providers which may set cookies in your browser.  Site activity information collected by these analytics providers may be combined with personal information held by PwC.  For more information about these third-party tools, please review our [Cookie Disclosure](https://www.pwc.com/us/en/site-information.html). 

To properly manage our Site we also log anonymous information on our operational systems and identify categories of visitors by items such as domains and browser types. These statistics are reported in the aggregate to our webmasters. This is to improve the web experience of our Site’s visitors and to provide us with an effective information resource.

When we send you emails, we may use technologies to determine whether the email has been opened and whether the links contained within the message have been clicked on. We may combine information collected through these means with other information we maintain about you in order to measure interest in our specific offerings and email campaigns, improve our offerings to specific target audiences, and tailor our interactions with you

##### **Information use**

We use the information we collect as described above for various purposes depending on the context in which we collected the information. For example, it may be necessary for us to process your information in order to process a transaction or provide a service you have requested or otherwise in accordance with a contract between us, or we may process your information in accordance with your prior consent (where you have provided such consent).

  * We also use the information we collect for the following business purposes:
  * Operating and improving the Site;
  * Fulfilling your orders and requests;
  * Managing your registration preferences;
  * Customizing the Site for you;
  * Understanding how the Site is being used;
  * Exploring ways to develop and grow our business;
  * Maintaining and improving the safety and security of the Site;
  * Preventing and enhancing protection against fraud, spam, harassment, intellectual property infringement, crime and security risks;
  * Sending you renewal notifications and/or service notifications;
  * Conducting customer satisfaction surveys;
  * Improving our products and services;
  * Running our operations;
  * Complying with law and legal obligations;
  * Responding to your inquiries; and
  * Sending communications about PwC products, services, and events.

##### **Information retention**

We will retain the personal information collected by us through the Site for as long as is necessary for the purpose(s) for which it was collected as set out in this privacy statement, provided that personal information may be held for longer periods where extended retention periods are required by law, regulation, or professional standards, and in order to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights.

##### **Information sharing**

We may share personal information with third parties as described in the **Information disclosure** section below.

In addition, our business contacts are visible to and used by other PwC member firms to learn more about a contact, client or opportunity they have an interest in.

##### **Third party sites**

Our Site may link to other websites which do not operate under PwC’s privacy practices. When you link to other websites, PwC’s privacy practices no longer apply. We encourage you to review each site’s privacy policy before disclosing any personal information.

##### **Children**

PwC understands the importance of protecting children’s privacy, especially in an online environment. The Site is not intentionally designed for or directed at children under the age of 13 years. It is PwC’s policy never to knowingly collect or maintain personal information about children under the age of 13

##### **Your choices** __

**Unsubscribe**

Should you wish to unsubscribe from our mailing list or any registrations, we will provide instructions in the appropriate area of the Site or in communications to you.

**Managing cookies**

If you are concerned about cookies, most browsers permit individuals to decline cookies. In most cases, you may refuse or delete one or more cookies and still access our Site, but Site functionality may be impaired. After you finish browsing our websites, you may delete Site cookies from your system if you wish.

**Do not track**

Do Not Track (“DNT”) is a privacy preference that you can set in your web browser to send a message to the website operator requesting not to be tracked. Currently, we do not respond to these DNT signals. For more information about DNT, visit [https://allaboutdnt.com](https://allaboutdnt.com/). ****

**Other rights**

For information about other rights you may have under applicable law, please see the **Individuals’ rights** section of this privacy statement.

##### **Your California privacy rights**

If you are a California resident, please click here for additional information about our processing of personal information and your California privacy rights.

#### Personnel

We collect personal information concerning our own employees (partners, principals and staff) as well as contractors as part of the administration, management and promotion of our business activities.

Please refer to the privacy statements available on PwC’s intranet for information on the collection and processing of your personal information in relation to your role with PwC.

#### Sourcing and recruitment of candidates

We collect and use personal information in connection with our sourcing activities, sometimes referred to as our “Talent Network” or “Talent Community,” and recruitment.  When joining our Talent Network or Talent Community, you can do so independently or through the US firm’s formal application process for an open position.

If you are formally applying for one of the firm’s open positions,  you will be presented separate privacy statements at the point of data collection during these processes. Should your formal application result in being being extended and accepting an opportunity to join the firm,  you will also be presented with privacy statements during the onboarding process. Please review those privacy statements for information about how PwC processes personal information in connection with recruitment and onboarding.

When providing information through the PwC US Careers webpage on our Site, please see the **Users of our websites and applications** section of this privacy statement for additional information about the collection and use of your information, including our use of Tracking Technologies. For more information about our use of Tracking Technologies, please review our [Cookie Disclosure](https://www.pwc.com/us/en/site-information.html).

##### Information collection

If you choose to join our Talent Network or Talent Community, which is independent of and may be done in conjunction with completing the firm’s formal employment application, we may collect the following personal information from you:

  * Contact details (e.g., name, email, telephone number);
  * Education, academic and professional qualifications;
  * Locations and interest in global opportunities;
  * Employment history;
  * Areas of interest and specialized knowledge/subject matter; and
  * Other information included on your resume/CV that you choose to submit.

We may also obtain the following personal information about you from third party sources:

  * Social media profile information, if you choose to provide us with a link to your profile page; and
  * Information from social media sites of which you are a member, specific to your engagement with our recruitment campaigns.

If you join our Talent Network or Talent Community during the recruitment application process, we may also use the information provided as part of your recruitment application for the purposes described below.

##### Information use

We use such personal information for the following business purposes:

  * To attract talent and market opportunities at PwC including by arranging, hosting and participating in events, marketing and advertising opportunities, including on social media, and using recruiters to help find talent for us.
  * To identify and source talent including by searching our talent pool and publicly available sources (such as professional networking and job websites of which you are a member).
  *  To evaluate you for open positions that match your interests and experience throughout the PwC network, manage your talent profile, send you email notifications and other announcements, request additional information or otherwise contact you regarding recruitment, events, thought leadership, or other opportunities we believe may be of interest to you.
  * To conduct statistical analyses and create reports, including regarding use of our careers websites, reports on PwC recruitment activities, analyses of candidate sourcing channels, and other requirements under US laws and regulations.
  * To administer and manage our careers websites and communicate with you about careers at PwC.
  * Any other purposes stated when you provide the information to PwC.

Please review the **Your choices**  section below for information about how you may unsubscribe from our mailing lists and exercise other rights.

##### Information retention

We retain the personal information processed by us for as long as is considered necessary for the purpose for which it was collected.  Personal information may be held for longer periods where extended retention periods are required by law, regulation, or professional standards and in order to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights.

##### Information sharing

We may share personal information with third parties as described in the **Information disclosure** __ section below.

##### Your California privacy rights

If you are a California resident, please click here for additional information about our processing of personal information and your California privacy rights.

#### Suppliers (including subcontractors and individuals associated with our suppliers and subcontractors)

##### Information collection

We collect and process personal information about our suppliers (including subcontractors and individuals associated with our suppliers and subcontractors) in order to manage the relationship, contract, to receive services from our suppliers and, where relevant, to provide professional services to our clients.  The personal information is generally business card data and will include name, employer name, phone, email and other business contact details and the communications with us.

##### **Information use**

We use such personal information for the following business purposes:

  * **Receiving services.  **We process personal information in relation to our suppliers and their staff as necessary to receive the services.  For example, where a supplier is providing us with facilities management or other outsourced services, we will process personal information about those individuals that are providing services to us.
  * **Providing professional services to clients.  **Where a supplier is helping us to deliver professional services to our clients, we process personal information about the individuals involved in providing the services in order to administer and manage our relationship with the supplier and the relevant individuals and to provide such services to our clients (for example, where our supplier is providing people to work with us as part of a PwC team providing professional services to our clients).
  * **Administering, managing and developing our businesses and services.  **We may process personal information in order to run our business, including:
    * managing our relationship with suppliers;
    * developing our businesses and services (such as identifying client needs and improvements in service delivery);
    * maintaining and using IT systems;
    * hosting or facilitating the hosting of events; and
    * administering and managing our website and systems and applications.
  * **Security, quality and risk management activities.  **We have security measures in place to protect our and our clients’ information (including personal information), which involves detecting, investigating and resolving security threats.  Personal information may be processed as part of the security monitoring that we undertake; for example, automated scans to identify harmful emails. We have policies and procedures in place to monitor the quality of our services and manage risks in relation to our suppliers.  We collect and hold personal information as part of our supplier contracting procedures. We monitor the services provided for quality purposes, which may involve processing personal information.
  * **Providing information about us and our range of services.  **Unless we are asked not to, we use business contact details to provide information that we think will be of interest about us and our services -- for example, industry updates and insights, other services that may be relevant and invites to events.
  * **Complying with any requirement of law, regulation or a professional body of which we   are a member. **As with any provider of professional services, we are subject to legal, regulatory and professional obligations.  We need to keep certain records to demonstrate that our services are provided in compliance with those obligations and those records may contain personal information.

##### **Information retention**

Personal information will be retained about our contacts at our suppliers for as long as it is necessary for the purposes set out above (e.g., for as long as we have, or need to keep a record of, a relationship with a contact, which is for the duration of our relationship with a contact or their organization). Personal information may be held for longer periods where extended retention periods are required by law, regulation, or professional standards and in order to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights.

##### **Information sharing**

We may share personal information with third parties as described in the **Information disclosure** __ section below.

**Your California privacy rights**

If you are a California resident, please click here for additional information about our processing of personal information and your California privacy rights.

#### Attendees of PwC events

We may collect personal information from attendees and participants of PwC-sponsored events. When we do so, such information is provided directly and voluntarily by the visitor.  Unless separate privacy terms are provided to the visitor at or in connection with the event, any personal information collected will be treated in accordance with the applicable section of this privacy statement.  ****

#### Visitors to our offices

We have security measures in place to protect our offices, such as secured entrance doors, visitor management procedures, security cameras, and an alarm activation system.

##### Security system

PwC offices are protected with security equipment at all entrance doors providing access control, auditing, and intrusion detection. The security camera system records activity at all entrance points and high security areas. The video images captured are securely stored and only accessed on a need to know basis for investigative purposes only (e.g., to look into an incident occurring at one of our locations).  The recordings are stored for a minimum of 90 days. We may disclose video images to law enforcement bodies as requested and permitted by data protection law.

##### **Visitor records**

We require all visitors to first be screened through our video intercom at our reception floor before we provide access into our reception area. When at the reception desk, the visitor will record their visit and be greeted by their PwC contact person. The visitor log is maintained by the receptionist and is only used for investigative or emergency situations.

##### **Guest WiFi**

We monitor traffic on our guest WiFi networks using industry standard intrusion detection systems. This allows us to see limited information about a user’s network behaviors but will include being able to see at least the source and destination addresses the user is connecting from and to. We cannot inspect any encrypted traffic and therefore do not have access to any information (personal or otherwise) that the user might share via encrypted connections.

##### Information sharing

We may share personal information with third parties as described in the **Information disclosure** __ section below.

##### **Your California privacy rights**

If you are a California resident, please click here for additional information about our processing of personal information and your California privacy rights.

#### Others who get in touch with us

We collect personal information (such as name, contact details and contents of the communication) when an individual gets in touch with us with a question, complaint, comment or feedback.  In these cases, we will only use the information for the purpose of responding to and keeping a record of the communication.  We may share personal information with third parties as described in the **Information disclosure** section below.

##### Your California privacy rights

If you are a California resident, please click here for additional information about our processing of personal information and your California privacy rights.

## Information disclosure

We will only share personal information with others for a business purpose and when we are legally permitted to do so.  When we share information with others, we put contractual arrangements and security mechanisms in place as appropriate to protect the information and to comply with our information protection, confidentiality and security standards. 

In addition to any information sharing practices described in the relevant section under Our Processing Activities, we share personal information with the following categories of recipients:

  * **Other PwC member firms**
    * For details of our member firm locations, please [click here](https://www.pwc.com/gx/en/about/office-locations.html).
    * We may share personal information with other PwC member firms where necessary for administrative purposes and to provide professional services to our clients (e.g., when providing services involving advice from PwC member firms in different territories).
    * We store personal information on our or other PwC member firm servers in the United States, EU and Singapore.  IT support and services are provided by PwC India and PwC’s IT Services company.
  * **Third party organizations that provide applications/functionality, data processing or IT services to us.**  We use third parties to support us in providing our services and to help provide, run and manage our internal IT systems -- for example, providers of information technology, cloud-based software-as-a-service providers, identity management, website hosting and management, data analysis, data back-up, security and storage services.  The servers powering and facilitating that cloud infrastructure are located in data centers around the world, and personal information may be stored in any one of them. Further details of significant third party providers are included below.

**Name**

| 

**Role**

| 

**Address**  
  
---|---|---  
  
Amazon Web Services (AWS), Amazon.com, Inc.

| 

Cloud IaaS and PaaS

| 

410 Terry Avenue N, Seattle, WA 98109, USA

Data centers located in a number of locations around the world (see AWS website)  
  
Google LLC

| 

Cloud collaboration tools

| 

1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA

Data centers located in a number of locations around the world (see Google website)  
  
Infosys

| 

Back-office IT outsourcing provider

| 

Electronic City, Bangalore, India  
  
Iron Mountain Inc.

| 

Shredding/document destruction and GDC media/hardware sanitization and destruction provider and backup tape rotation

| 

One Federal Street Boston, MA, 02110, USA  
  
Microsoft Corporation

| 

Cloud IaaS and PaaS

| 

One Microsoft Way, Redmond, WA 98052, USA

Data centers located in a number of locations around the world (see Microsoft website)  
  
Micro Focus International plc

| 

Laptop backup solution

| 

3000 Hanover Street, Palo Alto, CA, USA  
  
Oracle Corporation

| 

Software and cloud services

| 

500 Oracle Parkway Redwood Shores, CA 94065, USA  
  
Palo Alto Networks, Inc.

| 

Cloud network/infrastructure services

| 

3000 Tannery Way, Santa Clara, CA 95054, USA  
  
QTS Realty Trust, Inc.

| 

Data center hosting facility

| 

12851 Foster St. Overland Park, KS 66213, USA  
  
Salesforce.com, Inc

| 

Customer relationship management system

| 

415 Mission Street, 3rd Floor, San Francisco, CA 94105, USA  
  
Tata Consultancy Services (TCS)

| 

Back-office IT outsourcing provider

| 

Mumbai, Maharashtra, India  
  
  * **Auditors, professional advisors and insurers.  **We engage auditors and other professional advisors, for example, law firms, as necessary to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights and obtain advice in connection with the running of our business.  Personal information may be shared with these auditors and other advisors as necessary in connection with the products and services they have been engaged to provide. We also have a number of business insurance policies in place and we may need to share personal information with the insurer, for example, in the event of a claim. 
  * **Law enforcement or other government and regulatory agencies or to other third parties as required by, and in accordance with, applicable law or regulation.  **Occasionally, we may receive requests from third parties with authority to obtain disclosure of personal information, such as to check that we are complying with applicable law and regulation, to investigate an alleged crime, to establish, exercise or defend legal rights.  We will only fulfill requests for personal information where we are permitted to do so in accordance with applicable law or regulation. ****
  * **Third party organizations in connection with a corporate transaction.  **We may disclose your information to a third party as necessary in connection with a corporate reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of our business, assets or capital.
